brand,comment_id,text,subreddit,created_utc,score,sentiment,emotion,entities,topic
Intel,nxxeocb,Great.  Does this mean AMD will finaly stop pricing Strix Point as if it was made out of gold ?,hardware,2026-01-06 01:29:45,315,Positive,Surprise,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9983063), 'word': 'AMD', 'start': 23, 'end': 26}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.80161476), 'word': 'Strix Point', 'start': 52, 'end': 63}]",Tópico 1
Intel,nxxrlux,"One of the biggest things the current AMD driven handhelds lack is a decent upscaling option, so getting native XeSS support on a fast GPU would be a HUGE performance boost.",hardware,2026-01-06 02:39:52,107,Positive,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.90893614), 'word': 'AMD', 'start': 38, 'end': 41}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.7536994), 'word': 'X', 'start': 112, 'end': 113}]",Tópico 2
Intel,nxy2sll,"I think the LPE cores and them going at chiplets a second time after Meteor lake is paying off. This chip is more efficient than lunar lake, a chip that could do 0.62W idle lol.",hardware,2026-01-06 03:42:57,36,Positive,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9746815), 'word': 'LPE', 'start': 12, 'end': 15}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': np.float32(0.42433783), 'word': 'Met', 'start': 69, 'end': 72}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.5177657), 'word': '##eor', 'start': 72, 'end': 75}]",Tópico 1
Intel,nxy9wxm,"This is exciting. Hope some decently priced handhelds can drop, RAM prices notwithstanding.",hardware,2026-01-06 04:26:42,11,Positive,Joy,[],Tópico 1
Intel,nxxr090,am confused. this is battlemage too right? because its a B series. but its supposed to be all new. and the old gen was battlemage too on the 200V series. so what is going on here?. is this just a bigger GPU or is this Xe3 so that would be Celestial.,hardware,2026-01-06 02:36:35,22,Neutral,Surprise,"[{'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.727688), 'word': 'Celestial', 'start': 239, 'end': 248}]",Tópico 1
Intel,nxxhg0r,brah they straight up claiming it's equivalent to a 4050 on stream >!(a 60W RTX 4050)!<,hardware,2026-01-06 01:44:36,48,Neutral,Surprise,[],Tópico 1
Intel,nxykdxb,"Even if that claim were overstated by 2x, would still be a colossal L for amd.",hardware,2026-01-06 05:39:32,19,Negative,Neutral,[],Tópico 3
Intel,nxyc1w5,Xps is a huge seller for Dell and they are straight up using Panther Lake and XE3. They are exclusively going intel. Intel is 100% securing up there dominance in Labtops. In the process also taking business away from Nvidia.,hardware,2026-01-06 04:40:47,19,Positive,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.97185385), 'word': 'Xps', 'start': 0, 'end': 3}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9973959), 'word': 'Dell', 'start': 25, 'end': 29}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.6848141), 'word': 'Panther', 'start': 61, 'end': 68}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.7028222), 'word': 'Lake', 'start': 69, 'end': 73}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.95155746), 'word': 'XE3', 'start': 78, 'end': 81}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.99924916), 'word': 'Intel', 'start': 117, 'end': 122}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9797402), 'word': 'Labtops', 'start': 162, 'end': 169}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9705445), 'word': 'Nvidia', 'start': 217, 'end': 223}]",Tópico 2
Intel,nxxgruz,I hesitate to trust Intel's charts. But I am interested if Intel will actually get companies to adopt panther lake for their handheld pc. They did not have much luck with lunar lake.,hardware,2026-01-06 01:41:01,21,Negative,Fear,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9990522), 'word': 'Intel', 'start': 20, 'end': 25}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9990709), 'word': 'Intel', 'start': 59, 'end': 64}]",Tópico 1
Intel,ny1ifg6,"Assuming intel also keeps those mobile CPUs a good price, this could be really good. Hopefully as well they add the B390 in their high power desktop CPUs, seeing a core ultra 5 with an iGPU like this would really mitigate the need for a dedicated GPU right away Mostly because iGPUs on other generations were bad, and only a select few Ryzen CPUs had the 890M. Budget systems could become much better for gaming on the low side for graphical intensive games",hardware,2026-01-06 17:30:54,3,Positive,Neutral,[],Tópico 2
Intel,nxz4ji6,>Intel reference platform; Memory: 32GB LPDDR5 9600;  I wonder how much difference that makes and if we'll even see laptops with such RAM in this economy...,hardware,2026-01-06 08:34:38,4,Positive,Surprise,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.7227004), 'word': 'Intel', 'start': 1, 'end': 6}]",Tópico 1
Intel,ny34ie7,"I'd love to see benchmarks comparing it to lower end discrete GPUs (like 5050, B570, etc). Could be a boon for ultra low cost builds depending on what price point it lands at.",hardware,2026-01-06 21:54:52,2,Positive,Joy,[],Tópico 5
Intel,nxxyz1h,How many compute units does it have?,hardware,2026-01-06 03:20:58,4,Neutral,Neutral,[],Tópico 1
Intel,ny1ev6y,XESS and native frame gen is going to make handhelds monsters with Panther Lake in them.,hardware,2026-01-06 17:14:42,3,Neutral,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.5837264), 'word': 'Panther Lake', 'start': 67, 'end': 79}]",Tópico 1
Intel,ny0ibg4,I think people need to be ready for the fact that OEMs aren't going to use lpddr5x-9000,hardware,2026-01-06 14:42:06,1,Neutral,Neutral,[],Tópico 2
Intel,nxxd70q,"We'll see. Every year they claim they're faster, and every year they have been proven not to be",hardware,2026-01-06 01:21:44,-25,Neutral,Neutral,[],Tópico 4
Intel,nxxgaz9,NOTE: this might be because it has MFG (Multi-Frame-Generation).  We have to see reports to see if its true or not.,hardware,2026-01-06 01:38:30,-11,Neutral,Neutral,[],Tópico 3
Intel,nxxoge8,"This ain't gonna matter. It's the sku with 50% more igpu cores compared to lunarlake, which already has an igpu that's larger than the hx 370, it's real expensive. Imagine a hx370 with 26cu instead of 16, that's the price range you're lookin at  Any system built with this is gonna need to run at extremely high mem speed to feed the really large igpu which in the current market with insane ram prices is gonna be priced out of most people's budget. Are ya prepared for a gaming handheld that costs north of $1500?  And since this is gonna compete against nvidia's entry level mobile gpus oems are gonna have to choose between nvidia and intel for the gaming brand on laptops. Amd learned this through the hard way that most oems would choose nvidia over a large igpu.",hardware,2026-01-06 02:22:32,-12,Negative,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.5663239), 'word': 'Am', 'start': 678, 'end': 680}]",Tópico 1
Intel,nxykt3q,Haven't they been making similar claims for all their failed GPU's?,hardware,2026-01-06 05:42:44,-11,Negative,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.5533557), 'word': 'GPU', 'start': 61, 'end': 64}]",Tópico 1
Intel,nxyax11,"I mean Intel has never fudged the numbers before when they were behind, or do something crazy like literally bribe people.... Oh wait.... Uh.... Oh.....   Jokes aside, with what the current and future state of the market looks like, people might have to get used to iGPU graphics.",hardware,2026-01-06 04:33:13,-17,Neutral,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.99842477), 'word': 'Intel', 'start': 7, 'end': 12}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.9219114), 'word': 'iGPU', 'start': 266, 'end': 270}]",Tópico 1
Intel,nxyljzq,"To be fair it kind of is, the die size is huge, larger than an RTX 5070 die",hardware,2026-01-06 05:48:23,55,Neutral,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.77741516), 'word': 'RT', 'start': 63, 'end': 65}]",Tópico 1
Intel,nxxotcs,"Intel laptops were already better tbh, AMD had nothing to compete with Lunar Lake, and Arrow lake pretty much was better at high perf efficiency. Zen 6 better not be delayed or AMD will be buried under intel, qualcomm and apple all launching a real next gen shortly",hardware,2026-01-06 02:24:30,83,Positive,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.7624535), 'word': 'Intel', 'start': 0, 'end': 5}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9915668), 'word': 'AMD', 'start': 39, 'end': 42}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.8832488), 'word': 'Lunar Lake', 'start': 71, 'end': 81}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.69039655), 'word': 'Arrow', 'start': 87, 'end': 92}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': np.float32(0.51880085), 'word': 'lake', 'start': 93, 'end': 97}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.97338104), 'word': 'Zen 6', 'start': 146, 'end': 151}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9924505), 'word': 'AMD', 'start': 177, 'end': 180}]",Tópico 1
Intel,nxz1mq8,"Nah, because it's an ""AI chip"" and AMD will market it as so. AI equals fancy even though the AI capability can't match a regular desktop computer for far less.  Intel is probably gonna strategically match AMD in price.",hardware,2026-01-06 08:07:06,5,Neutral,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.8223918), 'word': 'AI', 'start': 22, 'end': 24}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9952675), 'word': 'AMD', 'start': 35, 'end': 38}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.7755668), 'word': 'AI', 'start': 61, 'end': 63}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.6664929), 'word': 'AI', 'start': 93, 'end': 95}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.99898463), 'word': 'Intel', 'start': 161, 'end': 166}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.97763294), 'word': 'AMD', 'start': 205, 'end': 208}]",Tópico 1
Intel,nxxvwrz,"With how wide the memory bus is, how much RAM it requires, nah the price is going up.",hardware,2026-01-06 03:03:31,23,Neutral,Neutral,[],Tópico 1
Intel,nxzxy26,it has soldered ram ... so it's better then gold!,hardware,2026-01-06 12:45:44,3,Positive,Neutral,[],Tópico 4
Intel,ny04wij,I guess that depends on Intel pricing too. Considering it's using both the latest TSMC and Intel foundries in one chip package. Not to mention the LPDDR5 9600.,hardware,2026-01-06 13:28:38,3,Neutral,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.99825436), 'word': 'Intel', 'start': 24, 'end': 29}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.7762504), 'word': 'TSMC', 'start': 82, 'end': 86}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9958417), 'word': 'Intel', 'start': 91, 'end': 96}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.76598436), 'word': 'LPD', 'start': 147, 'end': 150}]",Tópico 1
Intel,nxxhzsm,You mean OEMs.,hardware,2026-01-06 01:47:35,-11,Neutral,Neutral,[],Tópico 1
Intel,nxyn46u,No?  People will still value AMD more ue to brand so Intel will have to rely on volume for revenue  For reference only yesterday on this sub we had people talking about Intel lacking efficiency in comparison in mobile space,hardware,2026-01-06 06:00:32,-14,Neutral,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9442157), 'word': 'AM', 'start': 29, 'end': 31}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.99909854), 'word': 'Intel', 'start': 53, 'end': 58}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.99867487), 'word': 'Intel', 'start': 169, 'end': 174}]",Tópico 1
Intel,nxy8gkb,Crazy AMD haven't updated their iGPU to RDNA 4. I know they're probably waiting for UDNA but it would have been almost 3 years on the same architecture by the time we get the UDNA refresh next year (if they even bring it to their APUs right away). Sort of disappointing.,hardware,2026-01-06 04:17:21,67,Negative,Surprise,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9618705), 'word': 'AMD', 'start': 6, 'end': 9}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.57643294), 'word': 'R', 'start': 40, 'end': 41}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': np.float32(0.54940385), 'word': '##D', 'start': 41, 'end': 42}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.32976574), 'word': '##NA', 'start': 42, 'end': 44}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.5228047), 'word': '4', 'start': 45, 'end': 46}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.6853125), 'word': 'UDNA', 'start': 84, 'end': 88}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.6098007), 'word': 'UDNA', 'start': 175, 'end': 179}]",Tópico 4
Intel,nxxun0v,"tbf the most important issue is, few games implemented XeSS, just like AMD FSR.  And I think XeSS 3 being implemented in more games is a net positive for AMD GPU too.",hardware,2026-01-06 02:56:27,22,Positive,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.7498577), 'word': 'X', 'start': 55, 'end': 56}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.74946773), 'word': 'AM', 'start': 71, 'end': 73}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.5618245), 'word': '##D FSR', 'start': 73, 'end': 78}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.8198333), 'word': 'XeSS 3', 'start': 93, 'end': 99}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.925116), 'word': 'AM', 'start': 154, 'end': 156}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.53853655), 'word': '##U', 'start': 160, 'end': 161}]",Tópico 2
Intel,nxz85mh,"With everything happening around NVIDIA´s price increases and AMD´s lack of providing updates where it hurts, it **feels like** AI-Datacenters are more important right now for them (like the last 2 years).  But who can resent them as Intel had products that where not so much competitive that time.    Arrow lake (Desktop) at least closed on efficiency, but lacks a bit of gaming performance still, hopefully Nova Lake will be the step required to push more competition.   On GPU the same, AMD does not compete with NVIDIA in higher segments while NVIDIA is fairly comfortable with their setup and increases prices because they want to milk customers to increase their ridiculious margins (up to 70%) that they are used to from AI-Chips.   And now Intel also provides Multi-Frame generation, while a niche for me still, starting to compete with AMD and closes up to NVIDIA in terms of Software support, which they lacked the most and fixes a lot of problems.   Now let them release a B770 that is rumoured to be fairly mid/high range and we can hope for competition that actually learned from bad products recently and tries to make it better.",hardware,2026-01-06 09:09:24,10,Neutral,Anger,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9680256), 'word': 'N', 'start': 33, 'end': 34}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': np.float32(0.72281665), 'word': '##VI', 'start': 34, 'end': 36}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.8177253), 'word': '##DIA', 'start': 36, 'end': 39}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9883638), 'word': 'AMD', 'start': 62, 'end': 65}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.40747917), 'word': 'AI', 'start': 128, 'end': 130}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.99852115), 'word': 'Intel', 'start': 234, 'end': 239}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.63419586), 'word': 'Arrow', 'start': 302, 'end': 307}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.72120214), 'word': 'Des', 'start': 314, 'end': 317}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': np.float32(0.3566112), 'word': '##kt', 'start': 317, 'end': 319}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.92305064), 'word': 'Nova Lake', 'start': 409, 'end': 418}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9334769), 'word': 'GPU', 'start': 476, 'end': 479}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9939055), 'word': 'AMD', 'start': 490, 'end': 493}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.8644477), 'word': 'NVIDIA', 'start': 516, 'end': 522}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.97666895), 'word': 'NVIDIA', 'start': 548, 'end': 554}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.556033), 'word': 'AI', 'start': 728, 'end': 730}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.99859875), 'word': 'Intel', 'start': 748, 'end': 753}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9864105), 'word': 'AMD', 'start': 845, 'end': 848}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.7920584), 'word': 'NVIDIA', 'start': 866, 'end': 872}]",Tópico 1
Intel,nxz92l2,"Handhelds is a tiny tiny market, basing your product stack around them would be monumentally stupid.",hardware,2026-01-06 09:18:25,1,Negative,Anger,[],Tópico 1
Intel,ny0x7rg,"It may not beat LNL in very low power envelopes (LNL was designed for ~10W, PTL for 15W+), but it's a much, much better baseline than what Intel's historically had in client. Even just extending vaguely LNL-tier efficiency across the stack is a very big deal. Looks like Intel finally has a respectable SoC architecture. Now just need to get the cores and such in shape.",hardware,2026-01-06 15:54:14,12,Positive,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.99835664), 'word': 'LNL', 'start': 16, 'end': 19}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9970652), 'word': 'LNL', 'start': 49, 'end': 52}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9990225), 'word': 'Intel', 'start': 139, 'end': 144}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.5442794), 'word': 'L', 'start': 203, 'end': 204}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.998869), 'word': 'Intel', 'start': 271, 'end': 276}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.95105946), 'word': 'So', 'start': 303, 'end': 305}]",Tópico 5
Intel,ny4y069,"I mean the Xbox Ally X handheld is considered a $999 ""console"" so it sets the floor for what the Steam Deck and other handhelds would be priced at.",hardware,2026-01-07 03:37:21,1,Neutral,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.99781734), 'word': 'Xbox Ally X', 'start': 11, 'end': 22}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.54896474), 'word': 'Steam Deck', 'start': 97, 'end': 107}]",Tópico 1
Intel,nxxwdna,"It's branded as a Battlemage for some reason, but the architecture is Xe3. It's much closer to Celestial than it is to Battlemage.",hardware,2026-01-06 03:06:08,50,Neutral,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.98045117), 'word': 'Battlemage', 'start': 18, 'end': 28}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.7892212), 'word': 'Celestial', 'start': 95, 'end': 104}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.8775277), 'word': 'Battlemage', 'start': 119, 'end': 129}]",Tópico 1
Intel,nxxt4ce,"Battlemage is the brand name. The actual architecture of Lunar Lake is Xe2, same as desktop Battlemage, but they never explicitly called it Battlemage, only “Arc Graphics”.  What is meant to be desktop Celestial is Xe3P, but desktop Celestial is likely cancelled or significantly scaled back. Alchemist was a massive flop, and by the time the B580 came out to salvage Arc’s reputation the axe had probably already swung.",hardware,2026-01-06 02:48:07,8,Neutral,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.88184345), 'word': 'Battlemage', 'start': 0, 'end': 10}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': np.float32(0.60497135), 'word': 'Luna', 'start': 57, 'end': 61}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.7197683), 'word': '##r', 'start': 61, 'end': 62}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': np.float32(0.7106441), 'word': 'Lake', 'start': 63, 'end': 67}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.8787035), 'word': 'Battlemage', 'start': 92, 'end': 102}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.97192603), 'word': 'Battlemage', 'start': 140, 'end': 150}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9958449), 'word': 'Arc Graphics', 'start': 158, 'end': 170}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.6889602), 'word': 'Ce', 'start': 202, 'end': 204}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.70710224), 'word': '##les', 'start': 204, 'end': 207}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.8429147), 'word': '##tial', 'start': 207, 'end': 211}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.7398782), 'word': 'Celes', 'start': 233, 'end': 238}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.6087896), 'word': '##tial', 'start': 238, 'end': 242}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.6633269), 'word': 'Alchemist', 'start': 293, 'end': 302}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.9742866), 'word': 'B580', 'start': 343, 'end': 347}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.99771047), 'word': 'Arc', 'start': 368, 'end': 371}]",Tópico 1
Intel,ny7ef2l,It's a mid-gen refresh of battlemage.,hardware,2026-01-07 14:33:10,2,Neutral,Neutral,[],Tópico 5
Intel,nxxpiop,"They claimed ""10% faster"" than 4050   https://www.reddit.com/media?url=https%3A%2F%2Fpreview.redd.it%2Famd-is-done-v0-8op4m6l6bmbg1.jpeg%3Fwidth%3D1851%26format%3Dpjpg%26auto%3Dwebp%26s%3Df229e1ff0e364a6db90715de23ba799261ffe9e3",hardware,2026-01-06 02:28:19,54,Neutral,Surprise,[],Tópico 2
Intel,nxxqhlr,APUs are always way worse at gaming than synthetics when compared to a DGPU due to memory bandwidth limitation and power sharing with the CPU among other things like cache set up etc.  when they compare them to GPUs its always synthetics unless you get benchmarks of games,hardware,2026-01-06 02:33:43,22,Negative,Disgust,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.7358715), 'word': 'D', 'start': 71, 'end': 72}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.5563428), 'word': 'GP', 'start': 211, 'end': 213}]",Tópico 5
Intel,nxxl8hj,"Where's the bandwidth coming from?   Reviewers were saying that the 890m was bandwidth starved, so how can this chip be neck and neck with a recent dgpu with multiple memory channels",hardware,2026-01-06 02:05:05,9,Negative,Surprise,[],Tópico 1
Intel,nxy0hn7,60W is the laptop power draw. It looks like 30W for the 4050  this is the laptop they used for the comparison https://www.dell.com/en-us/shop/dell-laptops/dell-14-premium-laptop/spd/dell-da14250-laptop/useda14250hcto01#customization-anchor,hardware,2026-01-06 03:29:36,7,Neutral,Neutral,[],Tópico 1
Intel,nxy6cgs,"At best, it’s a 16% difference between a 100 watt and 60 watt RTX 4050 I believe, based on synthetic performance  Edit: Intel used a 30 watt 4050, this comment is incorrect",hardware,2026-01-06 04:04:08,1,Neutral,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9990011), 'word': 'Intel', 'start': 120, 'end': 125}]",Tópico 5
Intel,ny0ce80,What do you mean that a refreshed Strix Point can’t compete with an updated architecture?,hardware,2026-01-06 14:10:24,4,Neutral,Surprise,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.5501847), 'word': 'Strix Point', 'start': 34, 'end': 45}]",Tópico 1
Intel,ny0j8e4,"I got downvoted everytime I brought this up, but this is precisely why Nvidia wanted a deal to have an Nvidia iGPU tile on an Intel APU: Large iGPUs in thin and lights are going to get good enough over the next few years to make them the new entry-level graphics option for people. This directly threatens Nvidia's consumer laptop volume in the entry segment. Intel is claiming close to 4050 performance at this lower TDP, and that's certainly good enough for many to not have the tradeoffs of having a dGPU in their laptop.  If the new market is moving towards putting GPUs on the CPU package instead of discretely on the board, Nvidia doesn't want to place all of their hopes on WoA becoming better, and are hedging by doing both their own SoC *and* an x86 APU with Intel.  The XPS line dropping Nvidia discrete all together is proof of this. In these sub 70W total laptop power markets, a discrete GPU is just eats into the power budget too much.",hardware,2026-01-06 14:46:50,10,Neutral,Fear,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.970047), 'word': 'Nvidia', 'start': 71, 'end': 77}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.8287809), 'word': 'Nvidia', 'start': 103, 'end': 109}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.7660096), 'word': 'Intel', 'start': 126, 'end': 131}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.97200197), 'word': 'Nvidia', 'start': 306, 'end': 312}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.99870276), 'word': 'Intel', 'start': 360, 'end': 365}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9453352), 'word': 'Nvidia', 'start': 630, 'end': 636}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.79581004), 'word': 'So', 'start': 742, 'end': 744}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9968135), 'word': 'Intel', 'start': 768, 'end': 773}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.74663895), 'word': 'XPS', 'start': 780, 'end': 783}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.6480632), 'word': 'Nvid', 'start': 798, 'end': 802}]",Tópico 1
Intel,nxzgk6d,"In the ultraportables market (like XPS), integrated graphics just make so much sense (energy envelope; cooling system required; battery life; etc); and that's already substantial and before considering the cost of a NVIDIA mobile dGPU itself.  I don't understand why AMD decided to price Strix Point and Strix Halo so ridiculously -- it's their market for the taking.",hardware,2026-01-06 10:28:32,9,Neutral,Surprise,"[{'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.9079439), 'word': 'X', 'start': 35, 'end': 36}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.77929425), 'word': 'N', 'start': 216, 'end': 217}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': np.float32(0.814286), 'word': '##VI', 'start': 217, 'end': 219}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.8589088), 'word': '##DI', 'start': 219, 'end': 221}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': np.float32(0.3679985), 'word': '##A', 'start': 221, 'end': 222}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.99752516), 'word': 'AMD', 'start': 267, 'end': 270}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.82926923), 'word': 'Strix Point', 'start': 288, 'end': 299}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.60025924), 'word': 'St', 'start': 304, 'end': 306}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.42670396), 'word': '##rix', 'start': 306, 'end': 309}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.83815974), 'word': 'Halo', 'start': 310, 'end': 314}]",Tópico 1
Intel,nxzf0cx,I think they’re trying to take away business from Qualcomm/arm on windows before it takes off,hardware,2026-01-06 10:14:30,4,Neutral,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.95626813), 'word': 'Qualcomm', 'start': 50, 'end': 58}]",Tópico 4
Intel,nxxj6sm,Intel charts for their gpus have been pretty on point   Msi claw with lunar lake is one of the best handhelds,hardware,2026-01-06 01:54:01,63,Positive,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.99208635), 'word': 'Intel', 'start': 0, 'end': 5}]",Tópico 1
Intel,nxyetge,"Lunar Lake was a expensive product which didn't make sense in handhelds, Intel just didn't have anything else so they slapped that on the MSI Claw. Now the options should be much better considering they are selling a lower core Xe3 version for cheap too",hardware,2026-01-06 04:59:20,7,Negative,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9098708), 'word': 'Lunar Lake', 'start': 0, 'end': 10}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9981956), 'word': 'Intel', 'start': 73, 'end': 78}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.9969385), 'word': 'MSI Claw', 'start': 138, 'end': 146}]",Tópico 1
Intel,ny2yll4,"I'm just curious how they handle the need for such high speed RAM on desktop though? I guess this is an application where CAMM2 will be required, I don't think DDR5-9600+ is possible without it and this is presumably pretty key to the performance.",hardware,2026-01-06 21:27:43,5,Neutral,Surprise,"[{'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.87162185), 'word': 'CA', 'start': 122, 'end': 124}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.86361504), 'word': 'DDR', 'start': 160, 'end': 163}]",Tópico 1
Intel,nxzgr0g,"It certainly would make a huge difference because iGPUs are very memory bandwidth bound; and as the name suggests, LPDDR5 9600 has literally twice the bandwidth of the JEDEC standard 4800.  Unfortunately I doubt we'll see reasonably priced laptops with LPDDR5 9600 -- even as an add-on option. I've been eyeing Dells and Lenovos, and basically all SKUs that previously had 6000 are getting substituted with 4800; and many SKUs that were 2x16GB are now 1x16GB; yes **single channel**.... they charge you extra if you want 2x8GB.",hardware,2026-01-06 10:30:16,13,Neutral,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.641672), 'word': 'i', 'start': 50, 'end': 51}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.7683192), 'word': 'LP', 'start': 115, 'end': 117}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9965286), 'word': 'JEDEC', 'start': 168, 'end': 173}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.8511237), 'word': 'LP', 'start': 253, 'end': 255}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.8966319), 'word': 'Dell', 'start': 311, 'end': 315}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9691552), 'word': 'Lenovo', 'start': 321, 'end': 327}]",Tópico 1
Intel,nxyivuh,"It has 12 Xe3 cores. Intel doesn't use the term Compute Units, AMD does.",hardware,2026-01-06 05:28:14,12,Neutral,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9989281), 'word': 'Intel', 'start': 21, 'end': 26}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.8310378), 'word': 'Compute Units', 'start': 48, 'end': 61}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9920192), 'word': 'AMD', 'start': 63, 'end': 66}]",Tópico 1
Intel,nxxf8he,??? lunar lake has already shown to be faster than the 890m.  73 percent though seems like a bit much since panther lake was claimed to be around a 50 percent increase over lunar lake,hardware,2026-01-06 01:32:47,62,Neutral,Surprise,[],Tópico 1
Intel,nxxh29b,Example?,hardware,2026-01-06 01:42:33,13,Neutral,Surprise,[],Tópico 5
Intel,nxxhysy,"They did make a graph specifically to compare the performance of HX 370 and this Arc B390 while they were both using 2x upscaling, which is where this 73% number comes from. In another graph featuring supposedly ""native"" 1080p, they claimed Arc B390 was 82% faster than the HX 370 (why don't they just call it Radeon 890M though...)",hardware,2026-01-06 01:47:26,25,Neutral,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.96672267), 'word': 'HX 370', 'start': 65, 'end': 71}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.8365669), 'word': 'Arc B390', 'start': 81, 'end': 89}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.97546077), 'word': 'Arc B39', 'start': 241, 'end': 248}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.9790387), 'word': 'HX 370', 'start': 274, 'end': 280}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.98982483), 'word': 'Radeon', 'start': 310, 'end': 316}]",Tópico 2
Intel,nxxhhap,"No, intel claims 73% with upscaling (both) and 82% native",hardware,2026-01-06 01:44:47,17,Neutral,Neutral,[],Tópico 5
Intel,nxy83by,"If it was only a 73% gain *including* MFG, then that would be a serious performance regression. If they were using MFG in their graphs, it would easily be 200% - 300% ""faster"" at the same ""real"" performance",hardware,2026-01-06 04:15:06,5,Negative,Neutral,[],Tópico 5
Intel,nxxhnbn,"The graphs all listed games and I didn't see any synthetic benchmark scores were listed, so yeah.",hardware,2026-01-06 01:45:42,24,Neutral,Neutral,[],Tópico 5
Intel,nxxsvz8,The relative proportion of the die isn't as important as the die size itself and the node ofc.   Lunar lake for example has an estimated die size smaller than the hx370 so even if they did make the die bigger I don't think that is going to massively raise the price. Not to mention intel owns the foundry unlike AMD who are outsourcing to TSMC. This isn't in the realm of a strix halo competitor with a 300 mm\^2 + die size.   Dell for example has already refreshed the XPS line with intel panther lake and cut out the option for a dedicated gpu.,hardware,2026-01-06 02:46:52,18,Neutral,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.99780023), 'word': 'AMD', 'start': 312, 'end': 315}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.98812443), 'word': 'TSMC', 'start': 339, 'end': 343}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.99881685), 'word': 'Dell', 'start': 427, 'end': 431}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.95979613), 'word': 'XPS', 'start': 470, 'end': 473}]",Tópico 1
Intel,nxxhf0d,"There are 50% more GPU cores here than on Lunar or Arrow Lake. CPU is still 16 cores as well compared to Arrow Lake, just shifted from 6+8+2 to 4+8+4.",hardware,2026-01-06 01:44:27,27,Neutral,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.86871684), 'word': 'GPU', 'start': 19, 'end': 22}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': np.float32(0.7165936), 'word': 'Luna', 'start': 42, 'end': 46}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.5293693), 'word': '##r', 'start': 46, 'end': 47}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': np.float32(0.9029981), 'word': 'Arrow Lake', 'start': 51, 'end': 61}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': np.float32(0.7549185), 'word': 'Arrow Lake', 'start': 105, 'end': 115}]",Tópico 1
Intel,ny08rcj,"Do you mean Strix Halo?  Halo is made up of THREE dies. Two are regular CCD and one is a ~300mm2 graphics die. Total die area is around 440mm2 IIRC.  It's expensive, but not THAT expensive.",hardware,2026-01-06 13:50:17,33,Neutral,Surprise,"[{'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.84030914), 'word': 'St', 'start': 12, 'end': 14}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.9279121), 'word': 'Halo', 'start': 18, 'end': 22}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.8442995), 'word': 'II', 'start': 143, 'end': 145}]",Tópico 1
Intel,nxxs32m,Doesn't this depend on use case? AMD laptops are more capable for gaming and the iGPU can also use the lesser version of FSR. Intel is obv better for productivity.,hardware,2026-01-06 02:42:30,19,Positive,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.8166785), 'word': 'AMD', 'start': 33, 'end': 36}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9019485), 'word': 'i', 'start': 81, 'end': 82}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.7469847), 'word': 'F', 'start': 121, 'end': 122}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9982065), 'word': 'Intel', 'start': 126, 'end': 131}]",Tópico 1
Intel,nxzgbtp,"I disagree, Arrow lake HX seems to be more expensive than AMD HX as least on Lenovo Legion Pro setup.   I would have buy Arrow lake for the same price but AMD is cheaper by $200.",hardware,2026-01-06 10:26:24,3,Negative,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.8779942), 'word': 'Arrow lake', 'start': 12, 'end': 22}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.5673124), 'word': 'AM', 'start': 58, 'end': 60}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.38717932), 'word': '##D', 'start': 60, 'end': 61}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.7957694), 'word': 'Lenovo Legion', 'start': 77, 'end': 90}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.81829053), 'word': 'Pro', 'start': 91, 'end': 94}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.70818436), 'word': 'Arrow lake', 'start': 121, 'end': 131}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9903398), 'word': 'AMD', 'start': 155, 'end': 158}]",Tópico 1
Intel,nxy0jsm,Eh? It's a standard 128 bit memory bus.​,hardware,2026-01-06 03:29:57,37,Neutral,Neutral,[],Tópico 1
Intel,nxz8yd7,"You can't price it higher than people are willing to pay, how high that is I have no idea, people bonkers buying CPU only laptops at these high prices if gaming is something they really want to do.",hardware,2026-01-06 09:17:16,1,Negative,Surprise,[],Tópico 2
Intel,nxyjv70,Oems magically dont price intel variants as if they were made out of gold?,hardware,2026-01-06 05:35:35,6,Negative,Surprise,[],Tópico 1
Intel,ny2zhn1,"Lmao check the data, Intel has 79% of the laptop market share currently",hardware,2026-01-06 21:31:48,5,Neutral,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9585053), 'word': 'Lma', 'start': 0, 'end': 3}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.99917763), 'word': 'Intel', 'start': 21, 'end': 26}]",Tópico 1
Intel,nxz7zsg,"Reddit isn’t indicative of anything really, most casual laptop buyers don’t even know what AMD is.",hardware,2026-01-06 09:07:48,10,Negative,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.59943825), 'word': 'Red', 'start': 0, 'end': 3}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.6648858), 'word': 'AM', 'start': 91, 'end': 93}]",Tópico 2
Intel,nxzevm6,"I wouldn't be surprised if this is because the team has chosen to focus efforts on UDNA because that's the architecture next-gen consoles would use. They only have so much talent and headcount on their graphics division after all, and consoles have much higher volume (even tho low margins) and thus take priority.",hardware,2026-01-06 10:13:17,35,Neutral,Surprise,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9748586), 'word': 'UDNA', 'start': 83, 'end': 87}]",Tópico 1
Intel,ny7dxyt,AMD is planning on again using RDNA 3.5 on their next mobile chips as well.,hardware,2026-01-07 14:30:42,3,Neutral,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.99793303), 'word': 'AMD', 'start': 0, 'end': 3}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.7334048), 'word': 'RDNA', 'start': 31, 'end': 35}]",Tópico 1
Intel,nxy8549,Not an ideal solution but Optiscaler exists,hardware,2026-01-06 04:15:24,14,Negative,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.73249084), 'word': 'Optiscale', 'start': 26, 'end': 35}]",Tópico 4
Intel,nxzf3cy,"NVIDIA has increased margins but they haven't been that terrible. Part of the compounding issue at play is limited TSMC capacity; with both gaming and DC on the same TSMC node.  Ampere (crypto bubble ignoring) was priced well and many excellent cards in there since it was on Samsung, a cheap fab; while DC/workstation chips got TSMC.",hardware,2026-01-06 10:15:15,7,Neutral,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9968786), 'word': 'N', 'start': 0, 'end': 1}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.908523), 'word': '##VIDIA', 'start': 1, 'end': 6}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.712867), 'word': 'TSM', 'start': 115, 'end': 118}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.8270765), 'word': 'TSMC', 'start': 166, 'end': 170}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9979386), 'word': 'Samsung', 'start': 276, 'end': 283}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.74794185), 'word': 'TSM', 'start': 329, 'end': 332}]",Tópico 2
Intel,ny0vvvv,Who said anything about basing the entire product stack around handhelds?,hardware,2026-01-06 15:48:11,8,Neutral,Neutral,[],Tópico 1
Intel,ny13z79,"That's not quite right. Power levels are determined by the frequency of a given CPU core. The LPE cores in Lunar and Panther lake both clock up to 3.7 GHz, so given the added IPC of the new Panther lake e-cores and better process node, it is more efficient. Base power levels tell you nothing really.",hardware,2026-01-06 16:25:13,2,Neutral,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.77893364), 'word': 'LP', 'start': 94, 'end': 96}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': np.float32(0.77913636), 'word': 'Luna', 'start': 107, 'end': 111}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.3000439), 'word': '##r', 'start': 111, 'end': 112}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': np.float32(0.946085), 'word': 'Panther', 'start': 117, 'end': 124}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': np.float32(0.89543015), 'word': 'Panther', 'start': 190, 'end': 197}]",Tópico 1
Intel,nxz3zvx,"[It's actually closer to Battlemage than Celestial. Straight from Tom Petersen](https://youtu.be/P2AsCkKi-vs?t=1576)  >""Unfortunately that Xe3 name got decided years ago, it's actually spread around the Linux stack. Changing the name of that would have been very, very painful. So, that's why you're seeing this disjointedness abut Intel Arc ""B"" series. **Well, [Panther Lake] is B series because it's similar to Xe2** and we want to be transparent with our customers. Panther Lake has a new and improved GPU, that GPU is bigger and **it's very similar to B series.**""",hardware,2026-01-06 08:29:22,19,Neutral,Sadness,"[{'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.9179708), 'word': 'Battlemage', 'start': 25, 'end': 35}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.79928946), 'word': 'Celestial', 'start': 41, 'end': 50}, {'entity_group': 'PER', 'score': np.float32(0.9948977), 'word': 'Tom Petersen', 'start': 66, 'end': 78}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.5687085), 'word': 'X', 'start': 139, 'end': 140}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.931705), 'word': 'Linux', 'start': 203, 'end': 208}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.9504596), 'word': 'Intel Arc', 'start': 332, 'end': 341}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.8286949), 'word': 'Panther Lake', 'start': 363, 'end': 375}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.93609077), 'word': 'Panther Lake', 'start': 469, 'end': 481}]",Tópico 1
Intel,nxyzwrf,"Xe3 isn't Celestial, only Xe3P will be. See [https://www.tomshardware.com/pc-components/gpus/intels-xe3-graphics-architecture-breaks-cover-panther-lakes-12-xe-core-igpu-promises-50-percent-better-performance-than-lunar-lake](https://www.tomshardware.com/pc-components/gpus/intels-xe3-graphics-architecture-breaks-cover-panther-lakes-12-xe-core-igpu-promises-50-percent-better-performance-than-lunar-lake)",hardware,2026-01-06 07:51:09,11,Neutral,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.6992948), 'word': 'Celestial', 'start': 10, 'end': 19}]",Tópico 2
Intel,ny0y47o,"Yeah, it's a proper generational jump. Intel marketing is just dumb, and the comments from Peterson claiming Xe3 is somehow a smaller jump than Xe3p are just laughable.",hardware,2026-01-06 15:58:20,5,Negative,Disgust,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.99788755), 'word': 'Intel', 'start': 39, 'end': 44}, {'entity_group': 'PER', 'score': np.float32(0.99771047), 'word': 'Peterson', 'start': 91, 'end': 99}]",Tópico 1
Intel,nxyhb1s,The reason is marketing (the Battlemage brand is hot and filled with good will ATM so resetting to celestial so soon is not ideal regardless of panther Lake being xe³) Peterson addressed this a bit ago.,hardware,2026-01-06 05:16:46,1,Neutral,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9009454), 'word': 'Battlemage', 'start': 29, 'end': 39}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.8393162), 'word': 'AT', 'start': 79, 'end': 81}, {'entity_group': 'PER', 'score': np.float32(0.96807545), 'word': 'Peterson', 'start': 168, 'end': 176}]",Tópico 1
Intel,nxysdu1,Xe3p was alr confirmed coming im sure Celestial happens,hardware,2026-01-06 06:43:57,3,Neutral,Surprise,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.5177276), 'word': 'Celes', 'start': 38, 'end': 43}]",Tópico 1
Intel,nxzg5fp,"We will see, while Intel's PR and marketing is extremely confusing, Intel did confirm Xe3P will come to desktop; and at least from driver updates (as a very happy B580 owner) driver support has been constant and lively.  I had some issues with an older Civ game, I reported an issue in [their app](https://www.intel.com/content/www/us/en/support/articles/000057021/graphics/other-graphics.html) with screenshots/etc, and while I never got any notification, the game works perfectly now a few months later. Dunno if they read those reports, but my card keeps getting better.  I actually think a MSRP B580 is another card that will age like fined wine -- YMMV depends on games you play, but in Australia they have been regularly sold slightly below international MSRP and represent phenomenal value in the price class.",hardware,2026-01-06 10:24:47,1,Positive,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9983423), 'word': 'Intel', 'start': 19, 'end': 24}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.998176), 'word': 'Intel', 'start': 68, 'end': 73}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.6110299), 'word': '##3', 'start': 88, 'end': 89}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.6936207), 'word': 'Civ', 'start': 253, 'end': 256}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.6787712), 'word': 'MS', 'start': 594, 'end': 596}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': np.float32(0.9997714), 'word': 'Australia', 'start': 692, 'end': 701}]",Tópico 5
Intel,nxzdyw4,That's bloody good for an iGPU. It's been nice to see them finally get to respectable performance over the last few years. Intel in particular has really upped their iGPU game & it shows.,hardware,2026-01-06 10:05:03,20,Positive,Joy,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.6401358), 'word': 'i', 'start': 26, 'end': 27}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.8417806), 'word': '##GP', 'start': 27, 'end': 29}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9986106), 'word': 'Intel', 'start': 123, 'end': 128}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.877608), 'word': 'iGP', 'start': 166, 'end': 169}]",Tópico 4
Intel,nxxpg2g,not to mention it is a little skewed as they threw in a title which pushed the vram limit on the 4050 making the b390 over 800 percent faster in that title which obviously messes with the average.,hardware,2026-01-06 02:27:55,19,Negative,Neutral,[],Tópico 5
Intel,nxxsozj,It's 10% faster geomean across 45 games,hardware,2026-01-06 02:45:47,27,Positive,Neutral,[],Tópico 5
Intel,nxzfaqu,That can be resolved if either Intel or AMD decides to unlock quad-channel on consumer chips and mobos. It's artificial market segmentation; the die area needed to deliver more (LP)DDR5 channels is absolutely minuscule; for a huge boost in iGPU performance.,hardware,2026-01-06 10:17:06,2,Neutral,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9992249), 'word': 'Intel', 'start': 31, 'end': 36}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9983996), 'word': 'AMD', 'start': 40, 'end': 43}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.99401206), 'word': 'DD', 'start': 181, 'end': 183}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9236326), 'word': 'i', 'start': 240, 'end': 241}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.5807912), 'word': '##GP', 'start': 241, 'end': 243}]",Tópico 2
Intel,nxy0rol,Cache. Lots of it.,hardware,2026-01-06 03:31:13,23,Neutral,Neutral,[],Tópico 5
Intel,nxxpegk,"They are using 9600mt/s lpddr5x, could also have a lot of cache, (iirc 890m configs were nerfed in cache because they wanted to put a npu instead), and also could be a synthetic benchmark or specific game that isn't very bandwidth heavy.",hardware,2026-01-06 02:27:40,11,Neutral,Neutral,[],Tópico 5
Intel,nxxumwa,Panther Lake still has a 128 bit memory bus so only models with 9600 mt/s will get slightly faster shared memory bandwidth than Lunar Lake.   I wonder how this will manifest in games as the only performance leaks have been from Geekbench and 3DMark which may not be as bandwidth intensive as real games and applications.,hardware,2026-01-06 02:56:26,6,Neutral,Surprise,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.96692014), 'word': 'Panther Lake', 'start': 0, 'end': 12}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.8585322), 'word': 'Lunar Lake', 'start': 128, 'end': 138}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.960487), 'word': 'Geekbench', 'start': 228, 'end': 237}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.90330625), 'word': '3DMark', 'start': 242, 'end': 248}]",Tópico 1
Intel,nxy8e9t,"This seems to be correct, since checking NotebookCheck for the 30 watt 4050 shows that it’s around 70% faster than the HX370 in games, which is roughly where Intel places their iGPU.  The performance difference between a 30 watt 4050 and full 140 watt 4050 is around 41 percent performance based on Time Spy",hardware,2026-01-06 04:16:57,15,Positive,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.89894825), 'word': 'NotebookChe', 'start': 41, 'end': 52}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.91417384), 'word': 'H', 'start': 119, 'end': 120}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9983004), 'word': 'Intel', 'start': 158, 'end': 163}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.6565291), 'word': 'iGP', 'start': 177, 'end': 180}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.99424535), 'word': 'Time Spy', 'start': 299, 'end': 307}]",Tópico 5
Intel,nxy2xyi,"basically cheating tho, rtx cards in dell laptops are barely getting enough watts to even turbo",hardware,2026-01-06 03:43:51,4,Negative,Neutral,[],Tópico 1
Intel,nxzpm42,"That's the only way to do a fair comparison, really.   Because the 45 watts that Intel chip uses is shared for the entire chip.   So it's still 45w Intel + igpu vs 60w Intel+gpu",hardware,2026-01-06 11:45:18,1,Neutral,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.99808276), 'word': 'Intel', 'start': 81, 'end': 86}]",Tópico 1
Intel,ny0na4n,"It’s a super strong generational gain though, it’s like the jump from Vega 8CU to rdna2 12CU. The kind of single gen gain you see once in 5 years at most",hardware,2026-01-06 15:07:11,10,Positive,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.5032128), 'word': 'Vega', 'start': 70, 'end': 74}]",Tópico 5
Intel,ny2zoh2,The thing about that... what sort of tile are we expecting them to package up? As you say if we can get 4050ish performance from an Intel iGPU then they really can't be far off 5050M... and maybe even 5060M performance in future.  Do you think they'll offer something like a 5070 tile? that almost seems excessive (and difficult to actually package from a thermal point of view in a laptop) but it seems like the 5050/5060 sort of tier is going to be pretty well covered as a traditional iGPU soon.,hardware,2026-01-06 21:32:40,1,Neutral,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.5702771), 'word': 'Intel', 'start': 132, 'end': 137}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.42290708), 'word': 'i', 'start': 488, 'end': 489}]",Tópico 1
Intel,nxzk1m0,AMD actually introduced lower tier Strix Halos in this CES; and the first budget laptop thats gonna use it is [the Asus TUF A14](https://youtu.be/h27w0PXFBgk?si=Pa7UQhinywF-uFMj&t=306),hardware,2026-01-06 10:59:13,4,Positive,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.99800766), 'word': 'AMD', 'start': 0, 'end': 3}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.9657179), 'word': 'St', 'start': 35, 'end': 37}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.98029333), 'word': 'Halos', 'start': 41, 'end': 46}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.8613206), 'word': 'CES', 'start': 55, 'end': 58}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.8979513), 'word': 'As', 'start': 115, 'end': 117}]",Tópico 1
Intel,nxxklk7,They're a lot more accurate than whatever the fuck Nvidia has been doing where you have to decode their bar graphs for proper scaling lmao,hardware,2026-01-06 02:01:38,48,Negative,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.8886693), 'word': 'Nvidia', 'start': 51, 'end': 57}]",Tópico 5
Intel,nxzfsf4,"I'm pretty sure Intel threw lots of ""marketing money"" for the MSI Claw too. There were heaps of MSI Claw promotional booths / draws at shopping malls / public places in Australia and it was heavily discounted.  I picked one up for about $550 AUD (after rebates; tax included), which is like $369 USD inclusive of tax.",hardware,2026-01-06 10:21:31,2,Neutral,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.99854255), 'word': 'Intel', 'start': 16, 'end': 21}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.99659556), 'word': 'MSI Claw', 'start': 62, 'end': 70}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.9965164), 'word': 'MSI Claw', 'start': 96, 'end': 104}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': np.float32(0.99975413), 'word': 'Australia', 'start': 169, 'end': 178}]",Tópico 4
Intel,ny13km9,> Lunar Lake was a expensive product which didn't make sense in handhelds   What do you mean? All the tradeoffs LNL made were pretty good fits for a handheld.,hardware,2026-01-06 16:23:22,2,Neutral,Surprise,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.87287), 'word': 'Lunar Lake', 'start': 2, 'end': 12}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9985641), 'word': 'LNL', 'start': 112, 'end': 115}]",Tópico 1
Intel,nybz77q,"I don't think that will really be an issue, laptops can be configured with soldered 8 channel RAM like AMDs Z2 extreme, or they can still manage easily with regular DDR5 6400Mhz sodimms, which run at 102.4GB/s  Plus the CPUs that have intels new B390 iGPU are 4P/8E CPUs, so I doubt there will be much issues from low ram speeds. Something like the Radeon 890M have done fine with such speeds",hardware,2026-01-08 03:26:50,1,Neutral,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.9782581), 'word': 'DD', 'start': 165, 'end': 167}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.93955266), 'word': 'Radeon 890', 'start': 349, 'end': 359}]",Tópico 4
Intel,ny13z0b,"> I've been eyeing Dells and Lenovos, and basically all SKUs that previously had 6000 are getting substituted with 4800   You're looking at normal DDR, not LPDDR. LPDDR5-9600 *is* a JEDEC spec, and already available in mobile.",hardware,2026-01-06 16:25:12,6,Neutral,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9472619), 'word': 'Dells', 'start': 19, 'end': 24}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.96934783), 'word': 'Lenovo', 'start': 29, 'end': 35}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.37380943), 'word': 'LP', 'start': 156, 'end': 158}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.97894174), 'word': 'JEDEC', 'start': 182, 'end': 187}]",Tópico 1
Intel,ny020mx,"The majority of the lineup still only has 4. Will be interesting to see what the pricing and performance is on those since these will likely be quite limited. What's also a bit crazy is there's three different nodes being used for the various GPUs, and the full 12 unit one is probably on N3.",hardware,2026-01-06 13:11:40,2,Neutral,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.7445836), 'word': 'GP', 'start': 243, 'end': 245}]",Tópico 1
Intel,nxxlxrw,"I doubt it's exactly 73% outside of cherrypicked games, but it should not be shocking that it's significantly faster than rehashed rdna3.",hardware,2026-01-06 02:08:52,-1,Neutral,Surprise,[],Tópico 5
Intel,nxxjlfd,"Every Intel marketing benchmark for like a decade or so, but especially their GPUs seem to do far better in their benchmarks than they do in reality.",hardware,2026-01-06 01:56:13,-19,Positive,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.99876714), 'word': 'Intel', 'start': 6, 'end': 11}]",Tópico 5
Intel,nxxhxjk,"Ice lake, Alder lake, Metor Lake",hardware,2026-01-06 01:47:15,-20,Neutral,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': np.float32(0.82149154), 'word': 'Alder', 'start': 10, 'end': 15}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': np.float32(0.9609392), 'word': 'Metor Lake', 'start': 22, 'end': 32}]",Tópico 1
Intel,ny0aepy,"Different poster than OP.  Compute tile on Lunar Lake is 140mm2 on N3E with a small 46mm2 controller N6 tile. Strix Point (HX 370) as a whole is 233 mm2 on N4P. Lunar Lake is clearly cheaper, but given the newer node and packaging not massively so, likely by around 20-25%.  Panther Lake, with the B390, is going to be significantly more expensive than Lunar Lake. The B390 GPU has 50% more CUs, and that is very likely still on N3 or some variant (Intel only labeled this as external on their deck). CPU size 4xP+12xE as opposed to Lunar's 4+4, which should still be significantly more area with the core upgrades despite being on A18.  The ""mainstream"" variant also has the 4xP + 12 x E CPU, so even with the GPU being cut to 4 units it's likely somewhat more expensive than Lunar Lake.  Intel Foundry in general isn't any cheaper than TSMC. With Intel being practically the only user and development expenses it's likely more expensive than TSMC despite TMSC's margins. For all purposes it's an accounting trick to hide CCG's and DCAI's 5-15% operating margins if you divide the foundry losses per group revenue.",hardware,2026-01-06 13:59:25,1,Neutral,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.88849205), 'word': 'OP', 'start': 22, 'end': 24}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': np.float32(0.81835026), 'word': 'Lunar Lake', 'start': 43, 'end': 53}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9593021), 'word': 'Strix Point', 'start': 110, 'end': 121}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.87797374), 'word': 'Lunar Lake', 'start': 161, 'end': 171}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.861934), 'word': 'Panther', 'start': 275, 'end': 282}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': np.float32(0.56357145), 'word': 'Lake', 'start': 283, 'end': 287}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.80260754), 'word': 'Lunar', 'start': 353, 'end': 358}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': np.float32(0.5568131), 'word': 'Lake', 'start': 359, 'end': 363}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9976502), 'word': 'Intel', 'start': 449, 'end': 454}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.98091984), 'word': 'Lunar', 'start': 533, 'end': 538}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.86904067), 'word': 'Lunar Lake', 'start': 777, 'end': 787}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9962759), 'word': 'Intel Foundry', 'start': 790, 'end': 803}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.97438097), 'word': 'TSMC', 'start': 838, 'end': 842}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.99834), 'word': 'Intel', 'start': 849, 'end': 854}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9751096), 'word': 'TSMC', 'start': 944, 'end': 948}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9564794), 'word': 'TMSC', 'start': 957, 'end': 961}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.98046046), 'word': 'CCG', 'start': 1023, 'end': 1026}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9179949), 'word': 'DCAI', 'start': 1033, 'end': 1037}]",Tópico 1
Intel,nxxpvi7,"Yes, although the actual low power 8 core successor to Lunar Lake is the 335/365 with half GPU cores and slower RAM.",hardware,2026-01-06 02:30:19,-7,Neutral,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.42598116), 'word': 'Lunar', 'start': 55, 'end': 60}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.70722187), 'word': 'Lake', 'start': 61, 'end': 65}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.92022073), 'word': 'GP', 'start': 91, 'end': 93}]",Tópico 1
Intel,ny0b9nu,"even if you exclude the CPU CCDs the graphics die alone is bigger than a RTX 5070Ti mobile GPU, which also retails for \~$2000-$3000, same as Strix Halo laptop",hardware,2026-01-06 14:04:11,10,Neutral,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.6695217), 'word': 'R', 'start': 73, 'end': 74}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.65553015), 'word': 'St', 'start': 142, 'end': 144}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.62005126), 'word': 'Halo', 'start': 148, 'end': 152}]",Tópico 1
Intel,ny393aj,"This is slightly splitting hairs but the 8c CCDs in Strix Halo is actually NOT the same chiplet as the ones in desktop zen 5 parts. It iirc is produced on a smaller node, slimmed down, and has different ( or no) TSVs.  It is similar to design and cache sizes to desktop however, but the changes to the CCDs were done to improve low power performance characteristics. They are likely a bit more expensive than Desktop CCDs.  I believe it is discussed in a chips&cheese deep dive.",hardware,2026-01-06 22:16:26,3,Neutral,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.71754295), 'word': 'St', 'start': 52, 'end': 54}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.8661812), 'word': 'Halo', 'start': 58, 'end': 62}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.8989089), 'word': 'T', 'start': 212, 'end': 213}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.7786832), 'word': 'Desktop', 'start': 409, 'end': 416}]",Tópico 2
Intel,nxycvko,"AMD have largely been ""winning by doing nothing"" due to their better driver support stack for gaming on iGPUs, rather than actually throwing superior hardware at it.  It's almost ironic how AMD's mobile chipsets are now the ""Intel 14nm+++++"" of this generation.  Constant minor refreshes or even straight-up re-badges of old chips.  Now that Intel Arc has been around a while now and is getting quite capable.  I suspect Intel have a real opportunity to overtake AMD this generation in the iGPU space (ie. handheld and mini-PCs), especially since the new AMD APUs are just **another** refresh with a clock boost and Strix Halo is not scaled or priced to be actually affordable by normal people in that market.  XeSS can also act as a massive force-multiplier in power-constrained scenarios like handhelds.  AMD really shot themselves in the foot by either not building or not allowing FSR4 to function on RDNA3/3.5, which all current and now next gen AMD handhelds are stuck on.  Given how effective DLSS is on the Switch2, one could only imagine how kickass a Nvidia chip in a handheld PC could be with the far more ubiquitous DLSS support.",hardware,2026-01-06 04:46:15,78,Neutral,Surprise,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9844599), 'word': 'AMD', 'start': 0, 'end': 3}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9919697), 'word': 'AMD', 'start': 190, 'end': 193}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.99390405), 'word': 'Intel', 'start': 225, 'end': 230}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9917518), 'word': 'Intel Arc', 'start': 342, 'end': 351}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.99836713), 'word': 'Intel', 'start': 421, 'end': 426}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9593127), 'word': 'AMD', 'start': 463, 'end': 466}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.6094789), 'word': 'AM', 'start': 555, 'end': 557}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.53226656), 'word': 'St', 'start': 616, 'end': 618}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.8117597), 'word': 'Hal', 'start': 622, 'end': 625}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.94069374), 'word': 'X', 'start': 711, 'end': 712}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.6237776), 'word': '##SS', 'start': 713, 'end': 715}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9834733), 'word': 'AMD', 'start': 807, 'end': 810}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.48080888), 'word': 'F', 'start': 885, 'end': 886}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.7264869), 'word': 'R', 'start': 905, 'end': 906}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9346801), 'word': 'AMD', 'start': 951, 'end': 954}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.72268707), 'word': 'DL', 'start': 1000, 'end': 1002}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.8717853), 'word': 'Switch', 'start': 1015, 'end': 1021}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.7629416), 'word': 'N', 'start': 1061, 'end': 1062}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.51886684), 'word': 'DL', 'start': 1128, 'end': 1130}]",Tópico 1
Intel,nxyz1xa,Now they are not. The panther lake igpus are undisputed winners (excluding the 395+ from amd since it's just not gonna be mainstream). You can get a 358H or 368H and you'll have solid laptop for igpu gaming far cheaper than the 395+,hardware,2026-01-06 07:43:17,16,Positive,Neutral,[],Tópico 1
Intel,nxz8aui,"For business apps laptops have been good enough for 10 years now, iGPU and battery life is really the only differentiator.",hardware,2026-01-06 09:10:50,7,Neutral,Neutral,[],Tópico 2
Intel,nxxvlpa,"Intel is plenty competent for gaming, and has XeSS which is way better than FSR3.",hardware,2026-01-06 03:01:47,41,Positive,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9972772), 'word': 'Intel', 'start': 0, 'end': 5}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.8206305), 'word': 'XeSS', 'start': 46, 'end': 50}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.8710604), 'word': 'FSR3', 'start': 76, 'end': 80}]",Tópico 1
Intel,nxxx4hv,Lol? No 6 or 8 core 3dvcache laptops and no 5080 or 5090 laptops. Strix Halo is a joke for gaming as well,hardware,2026-01-06 03:10:21,-9,Negative,Surprise,"[{'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.49697188), 'word': 'St', 'start': 66, 'end': 68}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.7919377), 'word': 'Halo', 'start': 72, 'end': 76}]",Tópico 1
Intel,ny1dwcs,The 9955HX + 5070Ti is $2240 and the 275HX + 5080 is $2540.   When both 5070Ti configurations are on sale they should be the same price.,hardware,2026-01-06 17:10:18,3,Neutral,Neutral,[],Tópico 4
Intel,ny0f479,"It's about compromise. I don't *want* a 4lb laptop. I don't want a laptop that runs hot when web browsing. Or a laptop that has loud fans, or gets poor battery.  I have a desktop for gaming and other demanding tasks. For a laptop, I, and most of the market, want it focused on portability. Light weight. Cool running. Long battery. These big iGPU PTL laptops are really interesting because they provide *good enough* gaming without sacrifice to the non-gaming livability of the device.",hardware,2026-01-06 14:25:02,1,Neutral,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.87991846), 'word': 'iGP', 'start': 342, 'end': 345}]",Tópico 2
Intel,ny02zjc,"It took me way too long to convince my sister the AMD laptop I bought her isn’t going to blow up in her face and lose all her data, the Intel(and now Apple) CPU brands are very strong.",hardware,2026-01-06 13:17:30,2,Neutral,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.942193), 'word': 'AM', 'start': 50, 'end': 52}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9547865), 'word': 'Intel', 'start': 136, 'end': 141}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9946138), 'word': 'Apple', 'start': 150, 'end': 155}]",Tópico 1
Intel,ny0wejw,"> most casual laptop buyers don’t even know what AMD is  We're past that point now. Even ""normies"" have heard of AMD from news.",hardware,2026-01-06 15:50:32,1,Neutral,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.53566337), 'word': 'AM', 'start': 113, 'end': 115}]",Tópico 2
Intel,ny006yw,"its always ""fix it next generation"" with AMD.",hardware,2026-01-06 13:00:12,22,Negative,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9946804), 'word': 'AMD', 'start': 41, 'end': 44}]",Tópico 4
Intel,ny7wgeg,This is unfortunate news  (╥﹏╥),hardware,2026-01-07 16:00:09,1,Negative,Sadness,[],Tópico 5
Intel,nxyndbc,"I mean yeah it's not ideal, but you could argue it's the same with XeSS or FSR 4 on RDNA 3. Since the OP said ""there's no decent upscaling on AMD handheld"", therefore I assume Opsticaler is out of the question too.",hardware,2026-01-06 06:02:32,8,Negative,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.8672551), 'word': 'X', 'start': 67, 'end': 68}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.7175743), 'word': 'F', 'start': 75, 'end': 76}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.64809453), 'word': '##SR 4', 'start': 76, 'end': 80}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.5077035), 'word': 'R', 'start': 84, 'end': 85}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.49282143), 'word': '##D', 'start': 85, 'end': 86}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.9139587), 'word': '##NA 3', 'start': 86, 'end': 90}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.96774685), 'word': 'OP', 'start': 102, 'end': 104}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.62135077), 'word': 'AMD', 'start': 142, 'end': 145}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.68563724), 'word': 'Opstic', 'start': 176, 'end': 182}]",Tópico 1
Intel,nxzib6q,"Well you said it, it's TSMC capacity, meaning also a priority issue. They prioritize AI over consumers and then increase the price by reducing availability, meaning the same chip costs more, meaning more margin.  Seeing they increase the 5090 to roughly 5k (USD) is just the beginning and as I know all companies will use the increasing memory prices to say they must increase the product price, just not proportional to the memory costs.  next step: then they will use this to move more to streaming instead of owning",hardware,2026-01-06 10:44:14,-1,Neutral,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.88137895), 'word': 'TSMC', 'start': 23, 'end': 27}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.8368674), 'word': 'AI', 'start': 85, 'end': 87}]",Tópico 5
Intel,ny15kho,"> Power levels are determined by the frequency of a given CPU core   There are SoC and platform level targets that depend on a lot more than just clock speed for the same cores. Consider how LNL's PMICs scale vs FIVR/DLVR. Or what operating point benefits the most from the on package memory.   Especially at really low power, the cores are not your big concern. Consider the difference at 10W between 50% of your budget available for compute and 80%.   > so given the added IPC of the new Panther lake e-cores   We're talking a couple percent. DKT is a tick.    > and better process node   Very much unproven.    If you want to give credit somewhere, pretty much all of it should go to the SoC and GPU teams.",hardware,2026-01-06 16:32:30,3,Neutral,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.6791281), 'word': 'So', 'start': 79, 'end': 81}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9984298), 'word': 'LNL', 'start': 191, 'end': 194}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.36147287), 'word': 'Panther', 'start': 490, 'end': 497}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.8844711), 'word': 'So', 'start': 691, 'end': 693}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.82453316), 'word': 'GP', 'start': 699, 'end': 701}]",Tópico 1
Intel,ny0idmq,"Xe2, Xe3, etc. are the ""real"", more accurate names. Battlemage, Celestial are the marketing names.  Intel's decision to label the new Xe3 iGPUs as ""Battlemage"" is certainly an interesting (odd) choice - my best guess for this decision is that next year, Xe3P discrete will launch alongside Xe3P iGPU in NVL, and they're saving the new Celestial naming for that launch event.  Xe2 -> Xe3 is the bigger change.",hardware,2026-01-06 14:42:24,7,Positive,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.776569), 'word': 'Battlemage', 'start': 52, 'end': 62}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.72826976), 'word': 'Celestial', 'start': 64, 'end': 73}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9983627), 'word': 'Intel', 'start': 100, 'end': 105}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.8923721), 'word': 'X', 'start': 134, 'end': 135}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.6167281), 'word': '##3', 'start': 136, 'end': 137}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.93488884), 'word': 'Battlemage', 'start': 148, 'end': 158}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.58337295), 'word': 'X', 'start': 254, 'end': 255}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.53690165), 'word': '##3', 'start': 256, 'end': 257}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.6305538), 'word': 'X', 'start': 290, 'end': 291}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.57215315), 'word': '##3', 'start': 292, 'end': 293}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.92874175), 'word': 'Celestial', 'start': 335, 'end': 344}]",Tópico 1
Intel,ny1hu62,"Peterson states explicitly it's to take advantage of good Battlemage branding, around 1:30 of this video. [Intel Talks Xe3 Improvements For Gaming - YouTube](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Bjdd_ywfEkI)",hardware,2026-01-06 17:28:12,2,Neutral,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'PER', 'score': np.float32(0.99171644), 'word': 'Peterson', 'start': 0, 'end': 8}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.81061304), 'word': 'Battlemage', 'start': 58, 'end': 68}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9870697), 'word': 'Intel', 'start': 107, 'end': 112}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.63843083), 'word': 'YouTube', 'start': 149, 'end': 156}]",Tópico 1
Intel,ny0xhzi,"> Xe3p was alr confirmed coming  Not for client dGPUs, which are what get the Battlemage/Celestial brand.",hardware,2026-01-06 15:55:31,3,Neutral,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.81184906), 'word': 'Battlemage / Celestial', 'start': 78, 'end': 98}]",Tópico 1
Intel,nxy8fjz,"They also might be getting better value out of the ""2x scaling"" choice for benchmarking. Notice how they are behind Nvidia in all the none scaled titles except Dota2 that I saw.  Still very good results for a iGPU, but they are not entirely honest numbers either.",hardware,2026-01-06 04:17:11,14,Neutral,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9002609), 'word': 'Nvidia', 'start': 116, 'end': 122}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.99201536), 'word': 'Dota2', 'start': 160, 'end': 165}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.7408054), 'word': 'iGPU', 'start': 209, 'end': 213}]",Tópico 4
Intel,nxxshuz,It's 1 game out of 45 in geomean which devalues outliers. ~~9.9% faster instead of 10% faster if you take it out.~~  Edit: Oh no it's actually 6 FPS on the 4050. Yeah that's way too big for geomean to smooth out.,hardware,2026-01-06 02:44:44,23,Negative,Surprise,[],Tópico 5
Intel,nxy7k6w,And the fact they showed 45 games shows how confident they are in this product.  I remember the Intel slides with 5 hand picked titles we used to get just a few years ago.,hardware,2026-01-06 04:11:44,29,Positive,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9941016), 'word': 'Intel', 'start': 96, 'end': 101}]",Tópico 4
Intel,ny17afz,You mean in desktop? Or do you want mainstream mobile to go quad channel?,hardware,2026-01-06 16:40:20,3,Neutral,Neutral,[],Tópico 1
Intel,nxzgpgy,I wonder how 96MB cache would do had Intel put that much on it.,hardware,2026-01-06 10:29:53,3,Neutral,Surprise,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.99787414), 'word': 'Intel', 'start': 37, 'end': 42}]",Tópico 5
Intel,nxyig6s,They have 16 MB of L2 just for the GPU alone lmfao,hardware,2026-01-06 05:25:03,10,Neutral,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.8252379), 'word': 'GPU', 'start': 35, 'end': 38}]",Tópico 3
Intel,ny08xk6,> and also could be a synthetic benchmark or specific game that isn't very bandwidth heavy.  They're benching 45 games dude.,hardware,2026-01-06 13:51:15,6,Negative,Neutral,[],Tópico 5
Intel,nxyiiu1,"Also there's like 45 games on display here, it's not just 3dmark",hardware,2026-01-06 05:25:35,6,Neutral,Neutral,[],Tópico 4
Intel,nxy8oam,41 percent difference in performance compared to a full 140 watt in Time Spy. Honestly a bit surprised it isn’t more performance difference.,hardware,2026-01-06 04:18:43,5,Neutral,Surprise,"[{'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.9912677), 'word': 'Time Spy', 'start': 68, 'end': 76}]",Tópico 5
Intel,ny55i5l,"No, it's disingenous. Because everyone would think 60w 4050 = 60w on gpu alone",hardware,2026-01-07 04:22:58,0,Negative,Disgust,[],Tópico 4
Intel,ny384o8,"Not really sure. I believe it's Hammer Lake that's debuting the Nvidia tile, and that's rumored for a 2029 launch, so still quite a ways off, and 2 generations ahead of Blackwell.  The only rumors I'm aware of that it's going to be a pretty big iGPU",hardware,2026-01-06 22:11:51,5,Neutral,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.97596145), 'word': 'Hammer Lake', 'start': 32, 'end': 43}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.90812755), 'word': 'Nvidia', 'start': 64, 'end': 70}, {'entity_group': 'PER', 'score': np.float32(0.76047885), 'word': 'Blackwell', 'start': 169, 'end': 178}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.8218016), 'word': 'i', 'start': 245, 'end': 246}]",Tópico 2
Intel,ny7dl7u,"Nvidia's graphics have shown to be more efficient for space than both Intel and AMD, so whatever they use it will likely be better than what Intel can currently put out.",hardware,2026-01-07 14:28:52,2,Positive,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9767191), 'word': 'Nvidia', 'start': 0, 'end': 6}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9991264), 'word': 'Intel', 'start': 70, 'end': 75}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.99435127), 'word': 'AMD', 'start': 80, 'end': 83}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9990706), 'word': 'Intel', 'start': 141, 'end': 146}]",Tópico 1
Intel,nxzkp7q,Fantastic -- but at least six months too late ;),hardware,2026-01-06 11:04:52,5,Positive,Joy,[],Tópico 4
Intel,nxz5md2,You don't like graphs with zero scale claiming their latest 100W GPU is somehow a gazillion percent better than a 4090 or something?,hardware,2026-01-06 08:45:06,9,Negative,Disgust,[],Tópico 2
Intel,nxy8v6h,Wattage limited 4050 to 30 watts is the only slide that’s suspect.  It’s around a 41 percent performance loss based on Time Spy from the 140 watt 4050.,hardware,2026-01-06 04:19:56,7,Negative,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.9914365), 'word': 'Time Spy', 'start': 119, 'end': 127}]",Tópico 5
Intel,ny7raf2,I think they meant that the chip is very pricey which sucks because the handheld is already low-margin otherwisr and can't be priced too high else it got undercut by its competitors.,hardware,2026-01-07 15:36:28,1,Negative,Disgust,[],Tópico 1
Intel,ny0l0pv,The standard 4Xe models use the extra die space they save to have more PCIe lanes. that large iGPU adds cost and doesn't make much sense to use that chip if you're gonna add an Nvidia dGPU,hardware,2026-01-06 14:55:55,3,Negative,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.90485317), 'word': 'Nvidia', 'start': 177, 'end': 183}]",Tópico 1
Intel,nxxp4au,"yeah just looking at the game sample I can see a few that really don't perform well on RDNA architecture at least relative to nvidia(idk what really constitutes an ""intel favoured"" title)   Like stalker, csgo 2, civ vii, dying light the beast, and delta force ik run a lot better on nvidia relative to amd so im guessing the same holds true for intel vs amd.   A couple titles amd does well in were thrown in there too though like God of war and Cod but im guessing the real performance difference is more like 40-60 rather than the claimed 70-80.   Pretty large sample though which is nice so the numbers can't be that off.",hardware,2026-01-06 02:26:09,9,Negative,Surprise,"[{'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.96717405), 'word': 'RDNA', 'start': 87, 'end': 91}, {'entity_group': 'PER', 'score': np.float32(0.73040223), 'word': 'God', 'start': 431, 'end': 434}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.42779586), 'word': 'Co', 'start': 446, 'end': 448}]",Tópico 2
Intel,nxxtyhj,Why not?   It's 50% more cores + architectural improvements + clock  speeds,hardware,2026-01-06 02:52:42,10,Positive,Surprise,[],Tópico 5
Intel,nxzgxn6,"Please provide a **single** example in the past ~5 years of an Intel marketing benchmark that is materially inaccurate or untruthful.  NVIDIA is the one playing it loose with BS charts, AMD generally has a good track record (with some exceptions), and Intel on the GPU side has been pretty accurate. For example, these benchmarks have 45 games (!!) and use geomean to reduce outliers.  While I disagree with their choice of LPDDR5 9600MHz (hah, imagine a single consumer product shipping with that in this DRAM market), it is not untruthful.",hardware,2026-01-06 10:31:54,9,Negative,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.99800366), 'word': 'Intel', 'start': 63, 'end': 68}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.84415954), 'word': 'NVIDIA', 'start': 135, 'end': 141}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.9702191), 'word': 'BS', 'start': 175, 'end': 177}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9950719), 'word': 'AMD', 'start': 186, 'end': 189}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.99818915), 'word': 'Intel', 'start': 252, 'end': 257}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.6773672), 'word': 'GP', 'start': 265, 'end': 267}]",Tópico 5
Intel,nxxkps6,All were pretty accurate.,hardware,2026-01-06 02:02:15,18,Positive,Neutral,[],Tópico 5
Intel,nxxkqio,But lunar lake igpu actually perform better than 890M.Like comparison of core ultra 7 and z2 extreme in handheld like msi claw.,hardware,2026-01-06 02:02:23,15,Positive,Neutral,[],Tópico 1
Intel,ny0lzbq,">The ""mainstream"" variant also has the 4xP + 12 x E CPU, so even with the GPU being cut to 4 units it's likely somewhat more expensive than Lunar Lake.     The mainstream unit that's more directly comparable to LNL is the same core count (4+0+4) with a smaller iGPU tile. It'll be cheaper.  The 4+8+4 w/ 4Xe is the direct replacement to ARL-H, and that should also be cheaper than ARL-H.",hardware,2026-01-06 15:00:42,1,Neutral,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9485076), 'word': 'Lunar Lake', 'start': 140, 'end': 150}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9987109), 'word': 'LNL', 'start': 211, 'end': 214}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.695484), 'word': 'i', 'start': 261, 'end': 262}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.51074964), 'word': 'AR', 'start': 337, 'end': 339}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.55020845), 'word': '##L', 'start': 383, 'end': 384}]",Tópico 1
Intel,nxxvizf,"True, but then still, that's not a removal of CPU cores like they said it was.",hardware,2026-01-06 03:01:22,8,Neutral,Neutral,[],Tópico 5
Intel,ny3ft4h,That is due to the Nvidia tax and AI bubble rather than the production cost of the chip. Even Apple ships cheaper silicon than that.,hardware,2026-01-06 22:48:46,2,Neutral,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.83923763), 'word': 'Nvidia', 'start': 19, 'end': 25}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.9865307), 'word': 'AI', 'start': 34, 'end': 36}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9984043), 'word': 'Apple', 'start': 94, 'end': 99}]",Tópico 1
Intel,nxyibby,"This is very topical and cyclical of Intel/AMD. Intel did really poorly for like a half a decade which was unusual but usually they go back and forth. One gets lazy and incompetent, the other curated a masterful product that becomes dominant for a while and then they get lazy and it flips around.  Intel is planning on socketing a ton of cache on their next breed of chips which will massively boost their gaming perfomance and they have pretty darn efficient chips now too.",hardware,2026-01-06 05:24:04,15,Neutral,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.99921596), 'word': 'Intel', 'start': 37, 'end': 42}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.85495067), 'word': 'AMD', 'start': 43, 'end': 46}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9990853), 'word': 'Intel', 'start': 48, 'end': 53}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9992987), 'word': 'Intel', 'start': 299, 'end': 304}]",Tópico 1
Intel,nxygca9,Thank you for the thorough explanation! Very excited for the future of miniPCs and handhelds since there's so many games I'd like to play on the go.,hardware,2026-01-06 05:09:52,2,Positive,Joy,[],Tópico 2
Intel,nxz2wtv,"Yup, I am very happy to learn how wrong I was thanks to other people in this thread as well.",hardware,2026-01-06 08:19:04,7,Positive,Joy,[],Tópico 2
Intel,nxzn2om,"For business apps 10 years ago yes, now even Office has bloated itself up so much it's genuinely taxing even on the Apple chips  And well, the better the chip, the more outrageous the user workload gets. I appreciate the modern laptop chip's ability to import a CSV the size of Excel's row count limit and make a pivot table out of that, but now that it *can* do that I'm *expecting* that to be possible as quickly and as efficiently as possible.",hardware,2026-01-06 11:25:00,7,Negative,Anger,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9973591), 'word': 'Office', 'start': 45, 'end': 51}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.95094424), 'word': 'Apple', 'start': 116, 'end': 121}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.9412901), 'word': 'CS', 'start': 262, 'end': 264}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.95401394), 'word': 'Excel', 'start': 278, 'end': 283}]",Tópico 1
Intel,nxxy7wk,I was under the impression that XeSS needed a dedicated GPU? If it can run on iGPU that's a whole different story.,hardware,2026-01-06 03:16:38,-10,Neutral,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.98016506), 'word': 'XeSS', 'start': 32, 'end': 36}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.8050635), 'word': 'iGP', 'start': 78, 'end': 81}]",Tópico 1
Intel,nxz8pk3,"Their GPU's only look good when compared to 1 generation old bottom tier GPU's of their competitors. Its wild the praise they get.  Same thing will happen here, AMD will release a new iGPU architecture and Intel will be left comparing to out of date CPU's no one buys anymore.",hardware,2026-01-06 09:14:52,-5,Neutral,Surprise,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.86592877), 'word': 'GP', 'start': 6, 'end': 8}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.8185021), 'word': 'GP', 'start': 73, 'end': 75}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9983775), 'word': 'AMD', 'start': 161, 'end': 164}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.91904134), 'word': 'iGP', 'start': 184, 'end': 187}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.99802667), 'word': 'Intel', 'start': 206, 'end': 211}]",Tópico 1
Intel,nxxynsf,Sorry I should have specified that I'm talking about budget laptops with iGPUs.   I would sooner build a pc than even think about a 5080 laptop with 3dvcache options.,hardware,2026-01-06 03:19:11,15,Negative,Sadness,[],Tópico 1
Intel,ny01arz,"Yeah; meanwhile NVIDIA just released DLSS4.5 for **every single RTX GPU**... yes all the way back to Turing. It runs a lot better on more recent cards, but it's available on every single RTX GPU if you want to.",hardware,2026-01-06 13:07:13,17,Positive,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.99781704), 'word': 'N', 'start': 16, 'end': 17}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9108133), 'word': '##VIDIA', 'start': 17, 'end': 22}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.9372784), 'word': 'DL', 'start': 37, 'end': 39}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.6846624), 'word': 'R', 'start': 64, 'end': 65}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.8807465), 'word': 'R', 'start': 187, 'end': 188}]",Tópico 4
Intel,ny6k0v5,Except with UDNA it might be the first time over a decade AMD isn't phoning it in.,hardware,2026-01-07 11:22:51,1,Neutral,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9140324), 'word': 'UDNA', 'start': 12, 'end': 16}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9912425), 'word': 'AMD', 'start': 58, 'end': 61}]",Tópico 4
Intel,ny0x2bs,"XeSS and FSR 4 on RDNA 3 both use downgraded versions of those upscalers, that either look worse, perform worse, or both. In the case of FSR 4, it's a leaked one-off model that people got their hands on. All I really meant by ""decent"" was having an officially supported modern upscaler without all the downsides.  An Intel GPU running XeSS would presumably get the full version of XeSS without the performance hit and with good visuals.",hardware,2026-01-06 15:53:33,4,Negative,Disgust,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9102707), 'word': 'XeSS', 'start': 0, 'end': 4}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.8530681), 'word': 'F', 'start': 9, 'end': 10}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.70565534), 'word': '##SR 4', 'start': 10, 'end': 14}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.8285727), 'word': 'R', 'start': 18, 'end': 19}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.586959), 'word': '##DNA', 'start': 19, 'end': 22}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.74637866), 'word': '3', 'start': 23, 'end': 24}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.74905443), 'word': 'F', 'start': 137, 'end': 138}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.8782955), 'word': '##SR 4', 'start': 138, 'end': 142}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.6743106), 'word': 'Intel', 'start': 317, 'end': 322}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.80818236), 'word': 'X', 'start': 335, 'end': 336}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.45591083), 'word': '##SS', 'start': 337, 'end': 339}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9070912), 'word': 'X', 'start': 381, 'end': 382}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.58402026), 'word': '##SS', 'start': 383, 'end': 385}]",Tópico 1
Intel,nxzipnz,I can currently buy a brand new 5090 in Australia for $2841 USD with express postage included; I'm not sure why it's 5k USD in your region; but there's no reason you should be paying 5k USD. Which country are you in?,hardware,2026-01-06 10:47:45,5,Negative,Surprise,"[{'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': np.float32(0.99977046), 'word': 'Australia', 'start': 40, 'end': 49}]",Tópico 4
Intel,ny4uh4q,"The ultra X9 388H has a base TDP of 25W and minimal assured power draw of 15W. Meanwhile the ultra 7 155U has base TDP of 15W and minimal assured power draw of 12W. Both these numbers are lower for the meteor lake chip, yet the Panther lake chip is waaay more efficient (+2x). The base power level doesn't mean anything. It might be the point where the chip had the most perf/watt, but that doesn't mean that the performance at lower wattages is the same.",hardware,2026-01-07 03:17:13,-1,Neutral,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': np.float32(0.42457837), 'word': 'Panther', 'start': 228, 'end': 235}]",Tópico 5
Intel,ny0xx01,"Battlemage, Celestial, etc are named they (usually) use only for the dGPUs, even if that does correlate with the B/C-series naming. I think at some point this is just reading the tea leaves. The name's misleading for the tech difference.",hardware,2026-01-06 15:57:25,5,Neutral,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.98998), 'word': 'Ce', 'start': 12, 'end': 14}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.38652313), 'word': '##tial', 'start': 17, 'end': 21}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.6953291), 'word': 'd', 'start': 69, 'end': 70}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.83455426), 'word': 'B', 'start': 113, 'end': 114}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.64521044), 'word': 'C', 'start': 115, 'end': 116}]",Tópico 4
Intel,nxyibw6,XeSS FG has lower overhead than Nvidia IIRC,hardware,2026-01-06 05:24:11,5,Neutral,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9930698), 'word': 'XeSS FG', 'start': 0, 'end': 7}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9862469), 'word': 'Nvidia IIRC', 'start': 32, 'end': 43}]",Tópico 5
Intel,nxyaxye,If you actually do the maths it'd go down to (1.1^(45)/9)^(1/44) = 1.049 = 4.9% faster,hardware,2026-01-06 04:33:24,14,Neutral,Neutral,[],Tópico 4
Intel,nxysgiw,Mobile rtx 4050-70 maxes out at roughly 90-100 watts due to voltage limitation,hardware,2026-01-06 06:44:37,6,Neutral,Neutral,[],Tópico 5
Intel,ny3bk9e,"Oh wow that's a lot later than I expected, I was thinking this year or next.  Yeah no clue in that case.",hardware,2026-01-06 22:28:12,3,Negative,Surprise,[],Tópico 4
Intel,nxzfk6p,Infinity percent better at a feature the older GPU used for comparison does not support!,hardware,2026-01-06 10:19:28,1,Positive,Surprise,"[{'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.6725063), 'word': 'Infinity', 'start': 0, 'end': 8}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.6226281), 'word': 'GP', 'start': 47, 'end': 49}]",Tópico 4
Intel,ny0kqkf,"I don't really think that's ""suspect"". They said they're limiting the total laptop power on the 4050 to match the total laptop power of the PTL chip. If you want stronger performance out of a 4050, you're gonna need to have much higher power draw than the PTL laptop",hardware,2026-01-06 14:54:29,2,Neutral,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.6841887), 'word': 'PTL', 'start': 140, 'end': 143}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.68366706), 'word': 'PTL', 'start': 256, 'end': 259}]",Tópico 1
Intel,nxyj1tk,"CSGO is known for running like utter shit on Intel Arc, you can check r/IntelArc for details LOL. The game selection looks pretty reasonable to me.",hardware,2026-01-06 05:29:27,6,Negative,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.97289896), 'word': 'CSGO', 'start': 0, 'end': 4}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9865309), 'word': 'Intel Arc', 'start': 45, 'end': 54}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.75579274), 'word': 'IntelA', 'start': 72, 'end': 78}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.7809936), 'word': 'LOL', 'start': 93, 'end': 96}]",Tópico 2
Intel,nxy8v14,"Yeah all depends on pricing, 6 core ultra 5 model is however technically downgrade from last generation and the same core config as the i3 1315U.",hardware,2026-01-06 04:19:54,-2,Neutral,Neutral,[],Tópico 1
Intel,nxyk9c8,Honestly not that unusual. It takes an average of around 4-5 years to develop a processing unit from the ground up. If we assume each one does this when they get mushroom stamped by the other for being lazy it accounts for the 5 years gaps till they show back up with something to sell.,hardware,2026-01-06 05:38:33,22,Neutral,Neutral,[],Tópico 5
Intel,ny0dmdk,"I think AMD is getting a bit lazy when it comes to consumer graphics. I think their attempts at laptop have been really half-assed given just how good their IP portfolio is.  But when it comes to their core businesses, they're definitely been keeping the heat on and have been quite aggressive. They're datacenter first and foremost, and that trickles down to amazing desktop CPUs too. They're heavily focused on building out their Mi series too...but they're just dropping the ball in laptop and consumer GPU",hardware,2026-01-06 14:17:03,7,Negative,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9903866), 'word': 'AMD', 'start': 8, 'end': 11}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.8263165), 'word': 'Mi', 'start': 432, 'end': 434}]",Tópico 2
Intel,ny39k1v,Pantherlake also has an oddity in that it has MUCH higher L2 cache than even desktop zen 5 parts. I'm curious to see its CPU performance in low resolution scenarios.,hardware,2026-01-06 22:18:39,1,Neutral,Surprise,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.8549447), 'word': 'Pantherlake', 'start': 0, 'end': 11}]",Tópico 5
Intel,nxxyz2v,"The good version of XeSS runs on any chip with XMX units (Intel's version of tensor cores). Lunar Lake, Arrow Lake mobile, and now Panther Lake have GPU tiles with XMX units, so they get the same XeSS as discrete Arc cards.",hardware,2026-01-06 03:20:59,28,Positive,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.8554818), 'word': 'X', 'start': 20, 'end': 21}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.41308025), 'word': '##SS', 'start': 22, 'end': 24}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.65296566), 'word': 'XMX', 'start': 47, 'end': 50}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.99865425), 'word': 'Intel', 'start': 58, 'end': 63}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9822127), 'word': 'Lunar Lake', 'start': 92, 'end': 102}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9913931), 'word': 'Arrow Lake', 'start': 104, 'end': 114}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.99172235), 'word': 'Panther Lake', 'start': 131, 'end': 143}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.63864684), 'word': 'GP', 'start': 149, 'end': 151}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.68022066), 'word': 'X', 'start': 164, 'end': 165}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.75123084), 'word': 'Arc', 'start': 213, 'end': 216}]",Tópico 1
Intel,nxyty97,"Dedicated hardware, not dedicated GPU. The new Intel CPUs have iGPUs with the necessary hardware.",hardware,2026-01-06 06:57:17,6,Neutral,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.91104007), 'word': 'Intel', 'start': 47, 'end': 52}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.5051617), 'word': 'i', 'start': 63, 'end': 64}]",Tópico 1
Intel,nxy622y,"It needs dedicated GPU hardware to run faster, but they’ve started incorporating it on Lunar Lake and Panther Lake",hardware,2026-01-06 04:02:21,5,Neutral,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.91828036), 'word': 'GP', 'start': 19, 'end': 21}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': np.float32(0.96848315), 'word': 'Lunar Lake', 'start': 87, 'end': 97}, {'entity_group': 'LOC', 'score': np.float32(0.98906696), 'word': 'Panther Lake', 'start': 102, 'end': 114}]",Tópico 1
Intel,ny0e8rw,Intel has been very aggressive in the iGPU space. AMD isn't going to have any real updates to their iGPUs until 2027 the earliest.,hardware,2026-01-06 14:20:20,8,Neutral,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9987733), 'word': 'Intel', 'start': 0, 'end': 5}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.87920654), 'word': 'i', 'start': 38, 'end': 39}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9983981), 'word': 'AMD', 'start': 50, 'end': 53}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.5802092), 'word': 'i', 'start': 100, 'end': 101}]",Tópico 1
Intel,ny2bpjc,"> Same thing will happen here, AMD will release a new iGPU architecture   ... Based on what history? AMD's iGPU has not significantly changed in years. It's still hugely memory bottlenecked and no matter how many times they add an extra 2 CU's, it will still be memory bottlenecked.  IIRC someone disabled 2 CU's on their 7000 series APU and their in-game FPS almost didn't change because the bottleneck was actually memory access.  Intel ARC is actually very good on this metric. Intel doesn't exactly need to sling anything better than ""slightly more Battlemage on a better transistor"" to completely swamp out AMD iGPU in this space.",hardware,2026-01-06 19:42:26,1,Negative,Neutral,"[{'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9968641), 'word': 'AMD', 'start': 31, 'end': 34}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.7528491), 'word': 'iGP', 'start': 54, 'end': 57}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.99464107), 'word': 'AMD', 'start': 101, 'end': 104}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9950354), 'word': 'IIRC', 'start': 284, 'end': 288}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.75050116), 'word': 'F', 'start': 356, 'end': 357}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.7390294), 'word': 'Intel AR', 'start': 433, 'end': 441}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.9981357), 'word': 'Intel', 'start': 481, 'end': 486}, {'entity_group': 'MISC', 'score': np.float32(0.6366631), 'word': 'Battlemage', 'start': 553, 'end': 563}, {'entity_group': 'ORG', 'score': np.float32(0.7625046), 'word': 'AMD', 'start': 612, 'end': 615}]",Tópico 5
